PMP, CCNP Saudi Mobile No.:+966-55-0159054 • Jordanian Mobile Number+962-79-8807053 • Abed\_Alrabie@yahoo.com

## **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

A highly motivated and accomplished ICT professional with 10 years of experience in telecommunication, security systems and consultancy services industries. Over 6 years of extensive Project Management experience with a proven record of managing and leading infrastructure teams, coordinating with functional and testing teams, successful system integration and network management. Offers unmatched talents in managing and controlling project scopes and change control processes. Exemplified experience in project assistance and in identifying and communicating issues that may cause margin changes. Adept at handling multiple projects simultaneously and bringing them to completion in a timely and cost-effective manner.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- IT/ICT Project Management
- IP & AV Systems
- Project Budgeting & Planning
- Physical Security Systems CCTV
- IT Infrastructure & IT Operations
- Project Documentation
- Process Improvement
- System Integration
- Network Management

## **MAJOR CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Successfully managed to deliver multi-projects within challenging deadlines and budget limitations.
- Led the successful installation, configuration and maintenance of GENETEC Platform, GENETEC Security Center, Omnicast Server CCTV, Mobile Server and Plane Manager in addition to the Patroller AutoVu Fixed and Ipsotek System-Video Analytic System.
- Adept at installing, configuring, and maintaining security products connected through LAN and WAN networks.
- Managed to build effective basic infrastructure networks for physical security systems and IP base systems.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Inspire for Solutions Development• Riyadh, Saudi Arabia Project Manager

Jan 2022 to Present

Inspire for Solutions Development is an IT consulting company providing IT solutions throughout the Middle East (Jordan, Egypt, Iraq, Saudi Arabia, Qatar, UAE), with a discerning experience in helping organizations to quickly leverage IT solutions and to enhance the workflow of their businesses. (www.inspirejo.com)

## Key Responsibilities:

- Lead and coach project teams and drive successful delivery of projects.
- Develop schedule plans that support the business objectives, timelines, budgets, resources, milestones, and project deliverables.
- Work with Product Owner to ensure highest value features are delivered at agreed time.
- Actively participate in assisting the team in resolving issues and escalate as needed.
- Work with technical resources to coordinate outside part time resources as needed.
- Prepare and conduct periodic project status reports to update management regularly on progress, risks and issues.
- Manages project execution to achieve highest value project deliverables within the established schedule and budget
- Understand and help managing product backlog.
- Good Knowledge in tools like: Jira, Confluence, Slack .. Other.

## Saudi Media Systems • Riyadh, Saudi Arabia Project Manager

#### March 2015 to Dec 2021

Saudi Media Systems designs and integrates the electronic systems and infrastructure that enable voice, video, data and control communications across a common network. They provide consultancy services that includes needs assessment, physical surveys, conceptual system development, engineering, specifications and documentation. They also provides practical and innovative solutions for all types of applications: control centers, data visualization, integrated security and facilities management, networked media and data centers, video conferencing and eLearning. (www.smediasys.com)

## Key Responsibilities:

- Manage and control multiple complex ELV projects.
- Develop the Project Management Methodology for project team members.
- Establish scope, schedule and budgets of assigned projects.
- Develop detailed project execution plans and manage entire implementation processes including resource allocation, process tracking, monitoring change control process, risk identification, testing, documentation, training, on-time delivery within budget constraints.
- Provide overall communication and interface with all areas affected by the project including clients, consultants, cross-functional and other stakeholders.
- Lead internal and external resources, identify problems and resolve conflicts.
- Prepare and present required reports to all relevant stakeholders and clients regarding the project's progress concerning the scope, cost, and schedule.
- Oversee and develop the technical material submittal and shop drawings of the ELV projects.
- Manage contractual agreements with solution providers and vendors, and ensure adherence to product processes, quality standards, and deliverables.
- Manage and Understand ELV Systems as per Saudi Standard and International Standard.

# AREEN AL-AMEN Company LLC • Riyadh, Saudi Arabia Site Engineer

Dec 2013 - Jan 2015

A Saudi Company and a supplier for Public and Private Sectors with wide range of security products and customized solution. They provide their clients with new and advanced customized solutions that fulfil the exact needs, with allocated budget, and full after sales support.

### Responsibilities:

- Oversaw the security systems and projects implementation.
- Led, managed and motivated a team of 10+ support engineers and department staff.
- Followed-up and administered the execution and delivery of the project.
- Identified clients' requirements/complaints and planned, developed, and delivered optimal and efficient solutions.
- In charge of the administration, implementation and maintenance of LCS (CCTV, LPR, FR, Wireless communication solutions, detectors, etc...).
- Assumed the responsibility of monitoring and evaluating projects to ensure compliance with project plans.
- Built, developed and maintained strong relationships with partners and manufacturers.
- Provided reports for upper management and clients communicating progress, solutions, and recommendations.
- Managed and monitored service level performance through Service Level Agreements (SLA).
- Escalated project issues that cannot be completed within agreed service levels.

## **PREVIOUS ASSIGNMENTS**

## **KEY PROJECTS**

## Inspire For Solutions Development, Saudi Arabia

**Project Name:** Qiwa Wallet Project. Takamol, Riyadh **Project Type:** Payment Software Development.

**Project Specification:** Analysis and Design and develop the Qiwa wallet, in addition to the implementation,

testing, integration and handover.

Team Size: 12

### Saudi Media Systems, Saudi Arabia

**Project Name:** Ministry of Interior (MOI)-Headquarter, Jeddah **Project Type:** Audio Visual systems and Low Current systems

**Project Specification:** Designed the infrastructure of systems in addition to the implementation,

programing, testing, integration and handover.

Team Size: 20

## Saudi Media Systems, Saudi Arabia

Project Name: King Abdullah Bin Abdul Aziz for the Development of MOI Security Facilities -Phase 2B

**Project Type**: Physical security systems and AV systems

**Project Specification:** Designed the infrastructure of systems in addition to the implementation,

programing, testing, integration and handover.

Team Size: 28

## Saudi Media Systems , Saudi Arabia

**Project Name:** Imam University – EBMA buildings

**Project Type:** Networks infrastructure Active and passive systems.

**Project Specification:** Designed the infrastructure of systems in addition to the implementation,

programing, testing, integration and handover.

Team Size: 24

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree (BSc) in Computer Engineering, Yarmouk University, Jordan, 2011

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Project Management Professional Certification (PMP) -PMP Number: 2789286
- Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Mesbar Telecom Systems, Teleprobe, 2011

#### **TRAINING**

Physical Security Courses

GENET EC

- GSC-OTC (GENETEC Security Center Omni cast Technical Certification)
- GSC-AFC (GENETEC Security Center Patroller Auto Vu Fixed Certification) *IPSOTEK*
- Video Analytic System.
- Microsoft Certified System Administrator (MCSA), Yarmouk University, 2009

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

Member of ASIS International

# TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Ipostek-Video Analytic System
- GENETEC Platform & GENETEC Security Center- Omnicast Server CCTV, Mobile Server & Plane Manager
- MS SQL Server
- IP Addressing
- Networks Infrastructure
- Cisco Routers & Switches

# LANGUAGES

Arabic: Mother TongueEnglish: Very Good

# PERSONAL DOSSIER

Date of Birth: August 14th, 1988

Marital Status: Married

Gender: Male

• Nationality: Jordanian